# **CJ WILLIAMS**

## MARKETING DIRECTOR & UX PROFESSIONAL



**Phone** 406.579.1985



**Email** 

cj@silencekillsdesign.com



Website

hirecj.netlify.com

## SOCIAL



**Twitter**@s1lencek1lls



**Facebook** /cjwilliamsissilence



**LinkedIn**/cjwilliamsworks

#### EDUCATION

#### **Treehouse Academy**

Front-End Development Techdegree teamtreehouse.com 2014 - 2022

#### **Montana State University**

Graphic Design & Music Technology Bozeman, MT 2003 - 2008

## **SKILLS**

- UX / UI DESIGN
- HTML / CSS / JS
- VUE.JS / NUXT.JS
- ADOBE CREATIVE CLOUD
- MICROSOFT OFFICE
- SEMRUSH
- TECHNICAL SEO / SEM / PPC
- WORDPRESS / WOOCOMMERCE

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- GOOGLE ANALYTICS
- ADVANCED GOOGLE ANALYTICS
- HUBSPOT INBOUND
- MOZ SEO TRAINING

## PROFILE

Hey! Im CJ, a Marketing/E-Commerce Director, UX Systems Designer, and Front-End Web Developer with over 10 years of management experience. Scrappy and ambitious bootstrapper who wears many hats and loves learning. Accountable leader who grinds in the trenches with the team. Data-driven decision maker, always optimizing. Self-aware and open-minded jokester strapped with bad dad jokes aplenty. Admirer of driven peers, hard work, and frequently applaud my team's wins. Looking to join a team with shared goals, values, and ethics so we can make great things for the world.

#### EXPERIENCE

## **Hoists.com** (and sister companies: Sievert Electric, Sievert Crane, and CES) Marketing and E-Commerce Director / February 2021 - Present

- Architect of a growing dynamic product catalog for multiple brands and product configurations with forethought of ERP and API integration strategy
- Successfully launched Hoists.com to a reach of 14k unique visitors over its first two quarters, with 18k clicks, 1.8M impressions on a \$2k/mo. budget
- Led a scaling department and coordinated outsourced projects
- Persona research, brand strategy, brand development, and A/B testing
- Multi-site web development, JAMstack hybrid and cross-platform tracking
- Technical SEO, SEM, SMM, and PPC strategy, management, and reporting
- Assessment of product gaps and market-share expansion through market research, product research, and go-to-market strategies.
- Lead infrastructure development for Customer & Sales Support
- · Audio / Video / Digital asset production

## SilenceKillsDesign

Agency Owner & Front-End Developer / 2007 - 2020

- UX Research and Development for multi-million dollar national B2B clientele
- Managed multiple clients' online presence from conception to completion
- Designed SaaS admin interfaces for web apps for integration with Oracle
- · Brand asset design for digital and print mediums
- Website and e-commerce development, design, and optimization
- Persona research and development
- Owned SEO / SEM / PPC / SMM strategies, tracking, and reporting
- Track and report on KPI and goal completion in Google Analytics

#### **Xtant Medical**

Digital Marketing Manager / 2012 - 2016

- Designed and Developed public-facing site with constant A/B testing
- Developed investor and internal sales portals for access to private information, and product requests (internal e-comm) with a strong focus on UX/UI
- Location-based campaign advertising strategies around trade shows & events
- Managed a small team in web, email, social, and paid digital ad campaigns
- Adherence to ISO 13485:2003 quality standards and internal SOP creation
- · Ad buying, event planning, and trade show coordination with sales team
- Conceptualized and created all company and product branding